Historical Photograph Collection: Glass-Plate Negatives Series, 1880-1920: Preliminary Finding Aid AC317
University Archives
- Student Activities, 1890-1922; 17 boxes
  - Student activities, Lion Leap, Wilson & Cooke Animal Show, Branem Building, Princeton, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
  - Student activities, Lion Leap - afterwards, Wilson & Cooke Animal Show, Branem Building, Princeton, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
    Plate number: 1294
  - Student activities, movies of spring football, Goldie Field, 1915, 1 box (Box 67)
    Plate number: 1295
  - Student activities, movies of spring football, Goldie Field, 1916, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
    Plate number: 1296
  - Student activities, Hawaiian Sextet, Murray Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
    Plate number: 1297
  - Student activities, Hawaiian Sextet, Murray Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
    Plate number: 1298
  - Student activities, Poler's Session, 34 University Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
    Plate number: 1299-1300
  - Student activities, Poler's Session, recess, 34 University Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
    Plate number: 1301
  - Student activities, Poler's Session, at 1am, 34 University Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
    Plate number: 1302
  - Student activities, Poler's Session, at 1am, 34 University Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
  - Student activities, Princetonian-Cornell Sun baseball game, posing in front of Reunion, Undated; 1 box (Box 67)
  - Student activities, Princetonian-Cornell Sun baseball game, p-rading to the game, Undated; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1305
  - Student activities, Princetonian-Cornell Sun baseball game, tigers and widows swarming on field, Undated; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1306
  - Student activities, Princetonian-Cornell Sun baseball game, a widow touching base, Undated; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1307
  - Student activities, Princetonian-Cornell Sun baseball game, Bowman out at plate, Undated; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1308
  - Student activities, snowball fight 1918 vs. 1919, University Place, Undated; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1309
  - Student activities, snowball fight 1918 vs. 1919, University Hall, 1914; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1310-1311
  - Student activities, Student Pressing Agency, basdement Murray-Dodge, Undated; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1312-1313
  - Student activities, Student Pressing Agency, a load being brought in, Undated; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1314
  - Student activities, surveying civil engineering students near McCosh, Undated; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1315
  - Student activities, U-Store dividend time, Undated; 1 box (Box 68)
    Plate number: 1316-1317
  - Flying club, group of gents by plane, Undated; 1 box (Box 95)
  - Group of boys and men in choir robes against a stone wall, undated; 2 items (Box 113)
    These two negatives are broken.
- Individuals, 1914-1923; 14 boxes
  Glass plates within this series show individuals related to Princeton University.
  - Individuals, Poultney Biggelow, American journalist, traveler and author, Clio Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 69)
  - Individuals, Eugene Brieux, French dramatist and newspaperman, McCosh Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 69)
    Plate number: 1325
  - Individuals, Coach Bill Clark, Osbourne Field, Undated; 1 box (Box 69)
    Plate number: 1326
  - Individuals, Coan, William - Proctor, Undated; 1 box (Box 69)
    Plate number: 1327-1328
  - Individuals, Professor H.F. Covington, 34 Edgehill St., Undated; 1 box (Box 69)
    Plate number: 1329
  - Individuals, Professor Warner Fite, Prospect St., Undated; 1 box (Box 69)
    Plate number: 1330-1331
  - Individuals, Fite, Warner, Professor of Ethics, Undated; 1 box (Box 69)
    Plate number: 1332
  - Individuals, Hutson, Fred LeRoy, Classics Department, The Bachlors, Undated; 1 box (Box 69)
    Plate number: 1333
  - Individuals, Alfred Noyes, 1914, 1915?, circa 1914; 1 box (Box 69)
    See also Individuals - J. Duncan Spaeth
    Plate number: 1334
  - Individuals, Coach J.H. Rush, Undated; 1 box (Box 69)
    Plate number: 1335-1336
  - Individuals, Sam, the Brush Boy, front campus, Undated; 1 box (Box 70)
    Plate number: 1337
  - Individuals, Spadeit, the Peanut Man on William St., Undated; 1 box (Box 70)
    Plate number: 1338
  - Individuals, J.D. Spaeth and Alfred Noyes in coach's launch on Carnegie Lake, Undated; 1 box (Box 70)
    Plate number: 1339
  - Individuals, J. Duncan Spaeth coaching crew Alfred Noyes in boat with him, Carnegie Lake, Undated; 1 box (Box 70)
    Plate number: 1340
  - Individuals, William Howard Taft at Prospect, Undated; 1 box (Box 70)
    Plate number: 1341
  - Individuals, Woodrow Wilson with three men, Undated; 1 box (Box 70)
    Wilson in Princeton to vote for Women's Suffrage amendment to State Constitution. Paper print in Wilson Photos Box
    Plate number: 1342
  - Individuals, Woodrow Wilson with four men and cameraman, Undated; 1 box (Box 70)
    Plate number: 1343
  - Individuals, Woodrow Wilson shaking hands at train station, Undated; 1 box (Box 70)
    Plate number: 1344
  - Individuals, Woodrow Wilson with four men and cameraman, Undated; 1 box (Box 70)
    Plate number: 1345
  - Christian student, Undated; 1 box (Box 15)
    Plate number: 306
  - Jimmy Johnson with wheelbarrow, Undated; 1 box (Box 30)
    Plate number: 617
  - Ray Purdy and Jim Armstong in 10 E.M.W. winter of 1917, Princeton, 1 box (Box 31)
    Original sleeve No. 86
    Plate number: 618
  - D. Richardson 1922 of Princeton wireless clib in School of Science rooms, winter of 1919, 1 box (Box 31)
    Original sleeve No. 101
    Plate number: 632
  - Richardson, Murray and Grandin of wireless club in rooms in School of Science, Winter of 1919, 1 box (Box 31)
    Original sleeve No. 102
    Plate number: 633
  - Japanese speaker in Princeton, winter of 1919-1920, 1 box (Box 32)
    Original sleeve No. 110
    Plate number: 641
  - Dr. Grenfell, speaking at Alexander Hall, winter of 1919, 1 box (Box 32)
    Original sleeve No. 111
    Plate number: 642
  - Professor Paul Elmer More at his Residence on Nassau St., Princeton, spring of 1920, 1 box (Box 32)
    Original sleeve No. 112
    Plate number: 643
  - Dean McLenahan decorated with belgian medal by Cardinal Mercier, Sept., 1919, 1 box (Box 33)
    Original sleeve No. 122
    Plate number: 653
  - Cardinal Mercier addressing Princeton people from balcony of Prospect, Sept., 1919, 1 box (Box 33)
    Original sleeve No. 123
    Plate number: 654
  - Fred Baselt, Princeton, 1919, 1 box (Box 52)
    Original sleeve No. 495
    Plate number: 985
  - Edward Kurth, 1921, 1 box (Box 52)
    Original sleeve No. 496
    Plate number: 986
  - Bob Telfer, 1921, 1 box (Box 52)
    Original sleeve No. 497
    Plate number: 987
  - A.C. Blackwell, 1921, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 498
    Plate number: 988
  - Bob Mehl, 1921, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 499
    Plate number: 989
  - Harry Barton, 1921, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 500
    Plate number: 990
  - Willard Wattles in 1921, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 501. (with glasses)
    Plate number: 991
  - Willard Wattles in room 91, Undated; 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 502. (without glasses
    Plate number: 992
  - Buck Voorhees in room 91, Undated; 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 503. (Vertical)
    Plate number: 993
  - Buck Voorhees in room 91, Undated; 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 504. (Horizontal)
    Plate number: 994
  - Buck Voorhees and Willard Wattles, Undated; 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 505
    Plate number: 995
  - Ed Voorhees in room 104, Undated; 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 506. (Horizontal)
    Plate number: 996
  - Ed Voorhees in room 104, Undated; 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 507. (Vertical)
    Plate number: 997
  - Ralph Beebe, 1921, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 511
    Plate number: 998
  - Ralph Beebe, 1922, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 512
    Plate number: 999
  - Arthur Horton in khaki shirt, 1921, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 516
    Plate number: 1000
  - Arthur Horton, 1921, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 517
    Plate number: 1001
  - Elizabeth Tomlinson, 1922, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 527
    Plate number: 1002
  - Mr. and Mrs. Dugan, 1922, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 528
    Plate number: 1003
  - Ralph Beebe, S.K. Thomson, Arthur Horton, Harold Wahles, Mrs. Tomlinson, Elizabeth, and Mrs. Dugan, Undated; 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 529
    Plate number: 1004
  - Tex Wilson, 1922, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 530
    Plate number: 1005
  - Lino Castillejo, 1921, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 531
    Plate number: 1006
  - Jeff Webb and A.J. McDavid, 1922, 1 box (Box 53)
    Original sleeve No. 532
    Plate number: 1007
  - Mowbray Velte, 1921, 1 box (Box 54)
    Original sleeve No. 533
    Plate number: 1008
  - Artie Horton, Tubby Rahn and others at G.C., 1921, 1 box (Box 54)
    Original sleeve No. 537
    Plate number: 1009
  - Buck Voorhees (standing outdoors) 1921, 1 box (Box 54)
    Original sleeve No. 538
    Plate number: 1010
  - Saburo Chiba, 1921, 1 box (Box 54)
    Original sleeve No. 539
    Plate number: 1011
  - Tom Halsted, Kenneth Stevens, Garland Briggs, Tom Morrison, and Mae Richards, 1923, 1 box (Box 54)
    Original sleeve No. 662
    Plate number: 1015
  - Houston White, 1923, 1 box (Box 54)
    Original sleeve No. 663
    Plate number: 1016
  - Gregg Dougherty, 1923, 1 box (Box 54)
    Original sleeve No. 664
    Plate number: 1017
  - Lim Sprague, Dec., 1922, 1 box (Box 54)
    Original sleeve No. 667
    Plate number: 1020
  - No Description Available, Undated; 1 box (Box 54)
    Plate number: 1021
  - Lord Reading and his attendant in Princeton, 1918, 1 box (Box 55)
    Original sleeve No. 1028
    Plate number: 1034
  - Lord Reading speaking from Nassau Hall, 1918, 1 box (Box 55)
    Original sleeve No. 1030
    Plate number: 1036
  - Jim Robinson, Undated; 1 box (Box 55)
    Plate number: 1037
  - Recipients of honorary degrees, 1918, 1 box (Box 55)
    Original sleeve No. 1031
    Plate number: 1038
  - Cardinal Mercier leaving Alexander Hall after receiving honorary degree, 1919, 1 box (Box 55)
    Original sleeve No. 1037
    Plate number: 1043
  - Cardinal Mercier in faculty procession at Princeton, 1919, 1 box (Box 55)
    Original sleeve No. 1038
    Plate number: 1044
  - Hank Bovie, Proctor of the University, Undated; 1 box (Box 55)
    Original sleeve No. 1039
    Plate number: 1045
  - Lem Heyniger leading 1916 reunion singing at fall reunion 1918, 1 box (Box 56)
    Original sleeve No. 1059
    Plate number: 1065
  - Portrait of woman in victorian dress, Undated; 1 box (Box 98)
  - Portraits of Woodrow Wilson, undated; 2 boxes
    Glass plates within this subseries show portraits of Woodorw Wilson. In some instances, Wilson appears with other unidentified individuals.
    - Portrait, Woodorw Wilson in robes, Undated; 1 box (Box 98)
      8x10 Damaged plate with missing corner pieces
    - Portrait, Woodorw Wilson, different robes, Undated; 1 box (Box 98)
    - Portrait of Woodrow Wilson, Undated; 1 box (Box 112)
      8x10, broken
- Meetings, undated; 1 box
  Glass plates within this series concern meetings at the university.
  - Meetings, Billy Sunday, photographers waiting to snap him, Undated; 1 box (Box 72)
  - Meetings, Billy Sunday outside First Presbyterian Church with people to hear him. He is man in fur hat and coat with fur collar and cuffs., Undated; 1 box (Box 72)
  - Meetings, Billy Sunday making snowball outside First Presbyterian Church, Undated; 1 box (Box 72)
  - Meetings, Billy Sunday, students listening to him, First Presbyterian Church, Undated; 1 box (Box 72)
  - Meetings, Billy Sunday, students listening to him, First Presbyterian Church, Undated; 1 box (Box 72)
  - Meetings, men and women leaving McCosh Hall after lecture by Alfred Noyes, Undated; 1 box (Box 72)
  - Meetings, Pan-American Scientific Congress entering Nassau Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 72)
  - Meetings, Pan-American Scientific Congress entering Nassau Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 72)
  - Meetings, Pan-American Scientific Congress entering Nassau Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 72)
- Outdoor Scenes, 1899-1921; 9 boxes
  Glass plates within this series show outdoor scenes on the Princeton University campus.
  - Front campus in fall of 1919, 1 box (Box 48)
    Original sleeve No. 419
    Plate number: 914
  - Magnolia tree by 9 Hall, Undated; 1 box (Box 48)
    Original sleeve No. 423
    Plate number: 918
  - Blooming branch of Magnolia, 1921, 1 box (Box 48)
    Original sleeve No. 424
    Plate number: 919
  - Magnolia tree on front campus, Undated; 1 box (Box 48)
    Original sleeve No. 425
    Plate number: 920
  - Pathway between Witherpsoon and Little Halls, Undated; 1 box (Box 49)
    Original sleeve No. 426
    Plate number: 921
  - Magnolia flowering branch, Undated; 1 box (Box 49)
    Original sleeve No. 437
    Plate number: 932
  - Magnolia tree on front campus, 1917, 1 box (Box 58)
    Original sleeve No. 1125
    Plate number: 1123
  - Outdoor group scene, construction scene, Undated; 1 box (Box 90)
    Emulsion layer badly seperated
  - Outdoor scene, grad group, Undated; 1 box (Box 90)
  - Outdoor scene, grad group, women in center, Undated; 1 box (Box 90)
  - Outdoor scene with buildings, Undated; 1 box (Box 90)
  - Outdoor scene, one man with shovel of dirt, Undated; 1 box (Box 90)
  - Grad group around clock in square, Undated; 1 box (Box 90)
  - Outdoor graduation platform, speaker, Undated; 1 box (Box 90)
  - Group shot outside building, Undated; 1 box (Box 90)
  - Outdoor scene, chorus and church group, Undated; 1 box (Box 91)
  - Outdoor group shot, chorus?, Undated; 1 box (Box 91)
  - Large outdoor group shot with banner, 1899, large bird mascot (Puck), circa 1899; 1 box (Box 91)
  - Outdoor scene, building, possibly after fire damage, Undated; 1 box (Box 91)
  - Group shot, Armenian Flag, Undated; 1 box (Box 92)
  - Outdoor group scene, Undated; 1 box (Box 92)
  - Large group scene, chorus in gowns, outdoors, Undated; 1 box (Box 94)
  - Outdoor scene (chorus of graduation), Undated; 1 box (Box 94)
    Emulsion layer has seperated
  - Outdoor graduation scene, all seated, Undated; 1 box (Box 94)
  - Outdoor scene, Undated; 1 box (Box 94)
  - Foot bridge walkway, Undated; 1 box (Box 96)
  - Outdoor group, Undated; 1 box (Box 112)
    11x14, broken
  - Outdoor group, Undated; 1 box (Box 112)
- Indoor Scenes, undated; 3 boxes
  Glass plates within this series show indoor scenes on the Princeton University campus.
  - Students in front of fireplace in Third World Center, Undated; 1 box (Box 21)
    Plate number: 361
  - Indoor scene, men in classroom, Undated; 1 box (Box 91)
    Emulsion layer fragile
  - Large arched stain glass windows, Undated; 1 box (Box 91)
  - Indoor scene, chapel, Undated; 1 box (Box 91)
  - Indoor room, older men seated, Undated; 1 box (Box 91)
  - Indoor scene, classroom, faculty?, Undated; 1 box (Box 94)
  - Indoor scene, chapel, Undated; 1 box (Box 94)
  - Indoor scene, chapel, Undated; 1 box (Box 94)
- General Glass Plates, 1867-1923; 9 boxes
  Glass plate negatives within this series have no clear relation to other categories in the collection.
  - Silver cup, Undated; 1 box (Box 10)
    Plate number: 250
  - Faculty 1867/68, pictorial history p.26, 1867-1868; 1 box (Box 10)
    Plate number: 235
  - The Princetonian, pg. 1 of vol. 1, Undated; 1 box (Box 17)
    Plate number: 323
  - War poster exhibit in the library, winter of 1917-18, 1917-1918; 1 box (Box 31)
    Original sleeve No. 103
    Plate number: 634
  - Washington's birthday orators, Anderson 1921, Speir 1920 and McKee, 1919, Feb., 1918, 1 box (Box 31)
    Original sleeve No. 104
    Plate number: 635
  - Servian mission to U.S. leaving Princeton railroad station, January, 1918, 1 box (Box 32)
    Original sleeve No. 109
    Plate number: 640
  - Belgian Police dog of S.H. Thomson, spring of 1920, 1 box (Box 32)
    Original sleeve No. 121
    Plate number: 652
  - Fountain and garden on Mrs. Morgan's estate, Princeton, June, 1921, 1 box (Box 34)
    Original sleeve No. 290
    Plate number: 680
  - Flag on Pyne Tower at half mast at death of M. Taylor Pyne, Undated; 1 box (Box 34)
    Original sleeve No. 153
    Plate number: 685
  - "Dou" Weizel? June 1923, 1 box (Box 51)
    Plate number: 967
  - Deau Zuest? June 1923, 1 box (Box 51)
    Plate number: 968
  - Chaudles Italy? 1920, 1 box (Box 51)
    Plate number: 969
  - Mr. "Nike" June 1923, 1 box (Box 51)
    Plate number: 970
  - No Description Available, 1923; 1 box (Box 51)
    Plate number: 971
  - No Description Available, 1923; 1 box (Box 51)
    Plate number: 973
  - Little girl near Forest Glen, Ill, 1919, 1 box (Box 57)
    Original sleeve No. 1071
    Plate number: 1077
  - Girl in shorts, Undated; 1 box (Box 101)
  - Girl with toy tiger, Undated; 1 box (Box 103)
- Prints of Numbered Negatives, undated; 32 boxes
  This series consists of non glass plate materials. Numbered prints corresponed to respective numbered glass plates.
  - Palmer Lab construction, undated; 1 box (Box 114)
    Print number: 1-60. 8x10
  - Palmer Lab construction, undated; 1 box (Box 115)
    Print number: 61-132. 8x10
  - Buildings, undated; 1 box (Box 116)
    Print number: 133-184. 8x10
  - Buildings, undated; 1 box (Box 117)
    Print number: 185-240. 8x10
  - Buildings & grounds, undated; 1 box (Box 118)
    Print number: 241-277. 8x10
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 119)
    Print number: 1151-1190. 8x10
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 120)
    Print number: 319-322, 377-391, 1127-1150. 8x10
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 121)
    Print number: 1191-1210, 1406-1420. 8x10
  - Buildings, undated; 1 box (Box 122)
    Print number: 278-369. 11x14
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 123)
    Print number: 1286-1402
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 124)
    Print number: 392-675. 5x7
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 125)
    Print number: 676-950. 5x7
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 126)
    Print number: 1-305
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 127)
    Print number: 306-460, 564, 609, 618-721, 724-775
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 128)
    Print number: 951-1021, 1211-1222, 1403-1405. 5x7
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 129)
    Print number: 776-1100
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 130)
    Print number: 1022-1285
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 131)
    Print number: 1101-1222
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 132)
    Print number: 1-325
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 133)
    Print number: 326-630
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 134)
    Print number: 631-975
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 135)
    Print number: 976-1350
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 136)
    Print number: 1351-1700
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 137)
    Print number: 1701-2020
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 138)
    Print number: 2021-2312
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 139)
    Print number: 2313-2591
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 140)
    Print number: 2592-2889
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 141)
    Print number: 2890-2986, 2922-2973
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 142)
    Print number: Z2-1 to Z2-29, Z2-31 to Z2-37, 38-39, (2 strange Z2 numbers), Z3-1 to Z3-2
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 143)
    Print number: Z2-22 and Z2-30. 8x10
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 144)
    Print number: 1-200, 201-400, 401-700. 3 binders: Photocopies
  - No Description Available, undated; 1 box (Box 145)
    Print number: 701-1101, 1102-1402. 2 binders: Photocopies